Claire Standley (she/her): Okay, good morning welcome Dr Claude, we are so delighted to have you here today to talk a little bit about stakeholder identification, in the context of public health and so just to get us started, could you perhaps just briefly describe your your professional background.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). Доброе утро, доктор Клод, мы очень рады видеть вас здесь сегодня, чтобы поговорить немного об определении заинтересованных сторон в контексте общественного здравоохранения, и для начала не могли бы вы кратко рассказать о вашей профессиональной деятельности.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Thank you very much. I'm so happy to be with you
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Большое спасибо. Я очень рад участвовать
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: in this initiative, I am Claude Millogo and I am a medical doctor with a university public health a diploma and
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. в этой инициативе. Меня зовут Клод Милого, я доктор медицины с университетским дипломом в области общественного здравоохранения,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: I am currently the CDC and IANPHI consultant for Burkina Faso, but today I will not be speaking on behalf of CDC or the IANPHI but just I will be sharing with you my experience in supporting the NPHI [National Public Health Institute], so I have been working with
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. и в настоящее время являюсь консультантом Центров по контролю и профилактике заболеваний (CDC) и Международной ассоциации национальных институтов общественного здравоохранения (IANPHI) в Буркина-Фасо, но сегодня я не буду выступать от имени CDC или IANPHI, а просто поделюсь с вами своим опытом в программах NPHI [Национального института общественного здравоохранения]. Итак, я работаю с IANPHI,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: IANPHI, as you know IANPHI, the International Association of National Public Health Institutes. Since June 2018
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. то есть Международной ассоциацией национальных институтов общественного здравоохранения. С июня 2018 года
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: I have been working with the Ministry of Health and other partners to set up the NPHI in Burkina Faso. Okay, and also, I have served as the emergency consultant
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. я работаю с Министерством здравоохранения и другими партнерами над созданием NPHI в Буркина-Фасо. Также я работал консультантом по ЧС,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: the EOC specialist for VSO for polio, the EOC specialist for VSO, and working again with the Ministry of Health and also with the
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. специалистом центра управления в чрезвычайных ситуациях подразделения по борьбе с полиомиелитом НКО VSO, специалистом центра управления в чрезвычайных ситуациях VSO, а сейчас снова работаю в Министерстве здравоохранения и с
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: The global polio eradication initiative partners
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. партнерами Глобальной инициативы по ликвидации полиомиелита.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: and
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Да.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: I have been working in the field of public health for over 20 years with the government of the US, but in Burkina Faso and before joining IANPHI I
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Я более 20 лет отработал в сфере общественного здравоохранения при правительстве США, а в Буркина-Фасо и до прихода в IANPHI я
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: was the associate Peace Corps director here in Burkina Faso and supporting, helping, assisting the country director to develop and monitor, to implement, monitor and evaluate their community health.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. был помощником директора Корпуса мира в Буркина-Фасо и обеспечивал помощь, поддержку и содействие в разработке, внедрении, мониторинге и оценке общественного здоровья.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: And before that I was with USAID and UNICEF too, so I will stop here.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. А до этого я работал в Агентстве США по международному развитию и ЮНИСЕФ, так что на этом я, пожалуй, остановлюсь.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: For my background.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Относительно моего опыта работы.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Thank you.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Спасибо.
Claire Standley (she/her): I can see how it could take a long time to go through all of the many things that you've accomplished across your career, so thank you for that brief overview.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). Я понимаю, что перечисление всех Ваших достижений за всю карьеру может занять довольно долгое время, поэтому спасибо за краткий обзор.
Claire Standley (she/her): So so with respect to helping to set up Burkina is Burkina Faso's national public health institutes.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). Поговорим о помощи в создании национальных институтов здравоохранения Буркина-Фасо.
Claire Standley (she/her): And I know it's a relatively recent institution, so perhaps you could just briefly describe what the motivation for setting up the Institute was and and some of the context around that process.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). Я знаю, что это учреждение создано относительно недавно, поэтому попрошу Вас вкратце описать мотивы создания Института и некоторый контекст, связанный с данным процессом.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Okay, as you know, the Ebola epidemic.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Вспомним эпидемию Эболы.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Yes, it was really highlighting the urgent need to work to strengthen the national public health systems and in Burkina Faso, there was also the need to consolidate existing public health functions into a single entity to oversee disease control and response, the public health functions were scattered.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Да, она действительно подчеркивала срочную необходимость работы по укреплению национальных систем общественного здравоохранения, а в Буркина-Фасо также существовала необходимость консолидации существующих функций общественного здравоохранения в единую структуру для контроля над болезнями и реагирования, поскольку функции общественного здравоохранения были разрозненными.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: So it was important to really consolidate them and there was also a need to provide it, timely and evidence based response to public health issues
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Поэтому важно было действительно консолидировать их, а также обеспечить своевременное и научно обоснованное реагирование на проблемы общественного здравоохранения.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: and
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Да.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: And the establishment, the creation of the yes, the NPHI it also fits into the launch by the heads of the states of the African Union to establish the African CDC and establish National Public Health Institutes in each Member States.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Поэтому создание NPHI также вписывается в инициативу глав государств Африканского союза по созданию Африканских Центров по контролю и профилактике заболеваний, а также Национальных институтов общественного здравоохранения в каждой стране-члене.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: So the main objective of the creation of the Burkina
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Итак, основная задача создания NPHI в Буркина-Фасо
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: NPHI it the same for the other NPHIs as it is to meet the needs of strengthening health systems and the management for measuring health risks in public health and to support the global health security agenda right.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. та же, что и при создании других NPHI: удовлетворение потребностей укрепления систем здравоохранения и обеспечение управления для измерения рисков для здоровья в сфере общественного здравоохранения, а также для реализации глобальной повестки в области охраны здоровья.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: So it is very important to mention in that context the the high political will in Burkina Faso to establish the NPHI and the NPHI is even listed as a priority in the presidential program, so this is something important, and it was a great opportunity, how ever.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Поэтому очень важно отметить в этом контексте высокую политическую волю правительства Буркина-Фасо к созданию NPHI, и NPHI даже указан как один из приоритетов в президентской программе, так что это было действительно важное дело и прекрасная возможность,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: the Burkina NPHI was not established over night, the initiative to create such an institution has germinated since '98, imagine, also and finally happened in 2018 and it was created by a presidential decree.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. однако NPHI в Буркина-Фасо не был создан за один день: инициатива создания такого института вынашивалась – только представьте – с 98 года и, наконец, свершилась в 2018 году: центр был создан указом президента.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: by the President of the State.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Президента страны,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: that's very important to underline.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. это очень важный момент.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: The different national recognition and the NPHI is a public institution operating as part of the government and within the Ministry of Health.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Это совсем другой уровень признания, и NPHI является государственным учреждением, действующим как часть правительства и в рамках Министерства здравоохранения.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: That is for.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Вот что касается
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: The context of creation.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. контекста создания.
Claire Standley (she/her): And 20 years to get to this point, wonderful.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. И мы шли к этому 20 лет, даже не верится.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: We met in the beginning, I met with both people who really were the how to say the initiators.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. В самом начале пути я встречался с обоими инициаторами его создания.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: They talked about it and start talking and discussing how to implement it, it was impressive how difficult to establish the NPHI yeah.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Они рассказывали о проекте, обсуждали его внедрение, и это было впечатляюще, насколько трудно было создать NPHI.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: And to answer the question on which ministries, sectors and partner were involved, as you see, in addition to the President, who signed on it, in addition to the Ministry of Health, who sign on it, Minister of Health, in addition to the Minister of financial.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. И чтобы ответить на вопрос, какие министерства, отрасли и партнеры были вовлечены, помимо президента, министра здравоохранения, министра финансов,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: will sign on the decree.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. подписавших указ,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Important ministry involved in the establishment of the NPHI is the ministry in charge of research.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. отмечу, что одним из важных министерств, участвовавших в создании NPHI, было министерство науки.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Simply because.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Просто потому,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: NPHI includes three research centers.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. что NPHI включает три исследовательских центра.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: That were merged into the NPHI it was important, so the Ministry of Research was obviously involved, but in reality, the approach was.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Они были объединены с NPHI, это было важно, поэтому Министерство науки, несомненно, было вовлечено, но в действительности подход был таким.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: inclusive yeah I would say that the entire was was involved, since they discussed in the Council of Ministers, the establishment was discussed in the Council of Ministers before.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Я бы назвал его инклюзивным, поскольку была вовлечена вся структура: обсуждение создания велось в Совете министров.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: And they all agree and and then the decree was signed.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Все достигли согласия, и указ был подписан.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: say that the entire government.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Я имею в виду, что правительство в целом
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Was it was involved in that this is something that is important too.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. было вовлечено в этот процесс, и это важно.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: So two partners also were highly involved
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Также в создании NPHI участвовали
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: In the creation of the NPHI so to mention key partners who were involved, I consider US CDC and IANPHI.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. два ключевых партнера: Центры по контролю и профилактике заболеваний США (US CDC) и Международная ассоциация национальных институтов общественного здравоохранения.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: has supported the NPHI since the beginning for technical guidance and advice and financial support. Even the EOC
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Они с самого начала оказывали техническую и финансовую поддержку NPHI. В оперативном штабе
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: itself was even renovated, equipped and the staff trained by the US CDC so and other partners were also involved.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. был выполнен ремонт, произведено переоснащение, а сотрудники прошли обучение специалистами US CDC и других
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: partners who.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. партнерских организаций.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Yes, and also WAHO.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Следует также упомянуть WAHO,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Wolrd bank and, yes, the the partners were very supportive to the establishment of the NPHI.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Всемирный банк – партнеры оказали большую помощь в создании NPHI.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Other.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Еще один
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: key element key.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. ключевой момент.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: People or structures that were involved were well established NPHIs also yeah and.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Люди и организации, участвовавшие в создании NPHI,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: IANPHI has a well established network, and it has a well functioning approach for peer to peer support.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. имели отлаженную партнерскую сеть и функциональный подход к поддержке друг друга.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: So yes, the NPHI.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Итак, речь про NPHI.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: For example, in Santé Publique de France,Science a no, in Belgium, these are the other NPHIs that have really supported and were involved, also in the operationalization of the NPHI I think yeah.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Например, агентство Santé Publique de France, а также научное агентство из Бельгии стали партнерскими NPHI которые оказали значительную помощь в организации работы NPHI.
Claire Standley (she/her): Great and and with respect you know, obviously the NPHI is a national level Institute in Burkina Faso, but.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). Отлично и, несомненно, заслуживает уважения. Очевидно, что NPHI – это институт национального уровня в Буркина-Фасо.
Claire Standley (she/her): Did you have any engagement, also with sub national entities at the state, province, or the prefecture level in terms of understanding how the NPHI would play a role in public health across the whole country.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). Взаимодействовали ли вы с субнациональными организациями на уровне штатов, провинций или префектур в плане понимания того, как NPHI будет играть роль в общественном здравоохранении по всей стране?
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Yes.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Да.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Yes, among the stakeholders some, of course, there will be some national level.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Да, среди заинтересованных сторон, конечно, будут организации национального уровня.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Yes, and the "collectivités" is the local administrations, and the regional directorates of health.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. В сообщества входят местные администрации и региональные директораты здравоохранения.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: The districts, and to the Community, and it is important that even the Community.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Также районы, и очень важно, что задействованы местные сообщества,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: level is involved, we cannot do anything at the national levels if the structures that are in charge to implement and are not involved So yes, they were absolutely involved.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. местный уровень, поскольку невозможно все делать на национальном уровне, если ответственные на местах структуры не будут участвовать. Поэтому да, они участвовали в полной мере.
Claire Standley (she/her): And so, in your role is sort of gathering all of these different partners and stakeholders.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). То есть ваша роль заключается в том, чтобы собрать всех этих партнеров и заинтересованных сторон.
Claire Standley (she/her): Did you find that there were specific strategies that you used to bring them on board or to get their support, considering that there are many different types of stakeholders that you mentioned, from the World Bank to the.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). Были ли у вас какие-то конкретные стратегии, которые вы использовали, чтобы привлечь их к работе или заручиться их поддержкой, учитывая, что существует множество различных типов заинтересованных сторон, которых вы упомянули, от Всемирного банка до
Claire Standley (she/her): Community you know, this is a big range.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). местных сообществ – большой разброс.
yeah.
Да.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Since the beginning, and the NPHI Burkina Faso felt it's crucial to identify and engage the stakeholders, and we consider as stakeholders every organization or individuals that have interest in the work of the NPHI and/or all can help the NPHI achieve its mission so.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. С самого начала, руководство NPHI Буркина-Фасо считает, что очень важно определить и привлечь заинтересованные стороны, и мы считаем заинтересованными сторонами каждую организацию или отдельных лиц, которые заинтересованы в работе NPHI и/или все вместе могут помочь NPHI достичь поставленных целей работы.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: We need.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Нам необходимо
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: To, we need a synergy.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. достичь синергии.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: We need positive influence will also to reduce negative influence and we need to engage stakeholders for greater impact.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Нам необходимо положительное влияние, чтобы уменьшить отрицательные моменты, и мы должны привлекать заинтересованные стороны для большей эффективности.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: So that's it.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Как-то так.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: that's stage we wanted, through the stakeholder identification and engagement to obtain support for the NPHI.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. На этом этапе мы хотели через выявление и привлечение к работе заинтересованных сторон получить поддержку для NPHI,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: to obtain ownership.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. чтобы создать ответственность,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Of the NPHI, we needed ownership.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. за NPHI.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Thta's important
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Это важно.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: This is not something that is just for Burkina Faso, so it is your NPHI and we want to that, and it was important also to mobilize resources for.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Мы хотели донести, что NPHI принадлежит не только правительству Буркина-Фасо – это структура для всех, поэтому важно мобилизовать для нее ресурсы.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: The operationalization of the NPHI so that's where the key reason why we need to really to focus on the stakeholder identification.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Обеспечение функционирования NPHI – вот ключевая причина, по которой нам необходимо сосредоточиться на определении заинтересованных сторон.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: yeah.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Да.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: It was important to focus on organizations that were supporting.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Важно было сосредоточиться на организациях, которые оказывают поддержку.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: It was also important to focus on those who have negative influence, because, of course, the emphasis was the new structure and people could see that maybe there is a competition.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Также было важно сосредоточиться на тех, кто оказывает негативное влияние, потому что, конечно, акцент был сделан на новой структуре, и люди могли увидеть, что, возможно, существует конкуренция.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: In what they have been doing.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Тому, что они делают.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: So it was important to bring those people on board, with the help of those who are already supportive we needed them to bring on board those who are hesitant or considered the NPHI as a.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Поэтому было важно привлечь этих людей в нашу команду с помощью тех, кто уже нас поддерживает, а также нужно было привлечь тех, кто колеблется или рассматривает NPHI как...
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: As a hindrance to the world or competing competing with them and we need.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Как помеху их миру или соперничество с ними, и нам необходимо
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: to also take that into consideration.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. также это учитывать.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: We need to categorize them.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Нам необходимо разделить их на категории.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: categorize how? First the government entities, we need to this is a category and, within that category, you have those within the Ministry of Health.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Каким образом? millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Во-первых, правительственные организации: нам нужно, чтобы это была отдельная категория, и в рамки этой категории включаются сотрудники Министерства здравоохранения.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: And we have those in the government but are not within the Ministry of Health.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Есть также госслужащие, которые не входят в Министерство здравоохранения.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Okay, for example, the Ministry of research, I said, the Ministry of.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Это, например, представители Министерства науки,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: in charge of media all those
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Министерства массовых коммуникаций и пр.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: People yeah we needed to really focus on those to identify them and.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Нам нужно было определить всех этих людей
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: focus.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. и обеспечить фокус
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: On those also and.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. на них тоже.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: we spoke about government right and we also in the spirit of the One Health.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Итак, мы говорили о правительстве и о едином подходе к здравоохранению.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: This is a key point for the NPHI jBurkina Faso where we have to focus also and to include that in that group of government, all the ministries in charge of agriculture, of livestock, of environment, of obviously these groups, they needed to be in that group.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Это ключевой момент для NPHI в Буркина-Фасо, на котором мы должны сосредоточиться, и включить в эту группу правительства всех уровней, все министерства, отвечающие за сельское хозяйство, животноводство, окружающую среду.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: And, given the security issue also in Burkina it was important to.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. А с учетом проблем безопасности в Буркина-Фасо также было важно
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: include the military's etc those groups, yes.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. включить в эти группы военных и пр.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Yes.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Да.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: So a lot of categories, a platform, the government of course.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Итак, множество категорий, единая платформа, а также правительство,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: partners, the International Organization providing technical and financial support and World Bank, USAID, even though they were involved with the key stakeholders.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. партнеры, международная организация, оказывающая техническую и финансовую поддержку, Всемирный банк, Агентство США по международному развитию, даже несмотря на то, что они уже являются ключевыми заинтересованными сторонами.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: And another category is the.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Еще одной категорией будет
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: How do you call the private sector.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. частный сектор.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: yeah the private sector organization that was wanting, including these people talking with them, you can see that they want to help, and they even do not know how to help, so these people was very important to.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Да, частные организации, которые хотели бы помочь, но не знали как. Поэтому очень важно включить также этих людей.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: include and of course academics, the civil society, the civil society, the media, etc. you know civil society let's say that in Burkina Faso, we are lucky to have a very strong
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. И, конечно, представителей науки, гражданского общества, СМИ и пр. Следует отменить, что в Буркина-Фасо, к счастью, сложилось очень сильное
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Civil society with.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. гражданское общество, включающее
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: With associations of youth, of women and agriculturalists, all these people from top to bottom, so they are well-structured and it were important to involve them.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. ассоциации молодежи, женщин, работников сельского хозяйства, представителей всех слоев общества. Они имеют очень четкие структуры, поэтому важно их привлекать в качестве
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: into our stakeholders other key people of the faith
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. заинтересованных сторон. Также ключевую роль играют представители духовенства
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Opinion leader and yeah and yeah and they they're particularly were happy to be considered as a stakeholder.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. и лидеры мнений. Они были особенно рады войти в число заинтересованных сторон.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: For the NPHI
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. В отношении NPHI.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: So.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Итак.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: What was our approach to identifying exactly the groups, how do you get good at categorize them, so what was our approach.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Какой же подход мы использовали для точного определения этих групп и разделениях их по категориям.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: For example, a little reading the documents through reading the documents we realized that.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Например, проанализировав документы, мы поняли, что
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: There were groups of people who were established to think about the NPHI to analyze the situation and the social impact the etc, so this group of people, of course, important to include in the.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. уже существовали группы лиц, которые занимались вопросами NPHI, анализировали ситуацию, социальное воздействие и пр. Поэтому такие группы, конечно же, было необходимо включить
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Our stakeholders, they were key, in fact, because they have all the background they can explain things to the others, so that they can.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. в заинтересованные стороны. У них уже были необходимые знания и опыт, так что они могли консультировать других.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: be on board and document reading and also approaching those structures who were involved in the in the creation of the NPHI
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Поэтому мы их включили в число участников. Анализ документов также выявил структуры, участвовавшие в создании NPHI,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: meaning the Minister himself the Minister himself and his structures and talking with with the Minister of Health and asking according to you who are the other stakeholders that we need to to approach and.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. в частности, министра и его структуры. Мы обсуждали вопрос с министром здравоохранения и спросили его, кого необходимо включить в список заинтересованных сторон. Мы отметили, что нам нужен подход
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: cite the people, and we will list them in something when we are talking with the people who established the group that the NPHI, same question according to you, who are other.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. и список лиц, которые заинтересованы в деятельности NPHI. Мы со своей стороны тоже ведем работу с
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: stakeholders that have interest in the NPHI, they would decide it those who are supportive and said also those who are tempted to say no, we don't need an NPHI in that country so that was very, very useful and.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. потенциальными заинтересованными сторонами. Среди них есть те, кто готов оказывать помощь, а есть и противники, которые говорят, что в нашей стране NPHI не нужен. Так что эта работа была очень полезной.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Yes, asking question etc. Now to approach them we did one on one conversation with people we did focus group discussion and also we had stakeholder workshop, and we had partners Roundtable.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Задавать вопросы и пр. millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Далее, чтобы связаться с заинтересованными сторонами мы проводили обсуждения в фокус-группах, а также семинар для заинтересованных сторон и круглый стол для партнеров.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: You know.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Это понятно.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: So yeah and the one on one discussion with people.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Также были личные беседы с людьми.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: We wanted to listen to them and they wanted to express themselves, they really liked that you think they wanted to talk and see what they think about the NPHI.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Мы были рады выслушать их, а они высказать свое мнение. Им было действительно важно знать, что их позиция о NPHI нас интересует.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: I was, I went for 15 to 20 minutes of discussion and I found myself discussing for one hour even sometimes for two hours because people want to express themselves.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr.  Я планировал обсуждение на 15-20 минут, но обнаружил, что беседую по часу, а иногда и по два часа, потому что люди хотят высказаться.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: yeah we are yeah me just ask them about a establishment of the NPHI, their concerns what they think the NPHI will bring to their structure and vice versa, and if they had suggestion, so that they.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Я спрашивал их о создании NPHI, их опасениях, что, по их мнению, NPHI привнесет в их структуру и наоборот, а также есть ли у них предложения по
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: can be.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. организации
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: operational and things like that, so they really liked that we and we we we summarize all these things, then what they said their concerns, what the NPHI can offer to to to the Ministry, to the government to them, etc, we went with a document on that and we presented that at the.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. работы. Им очень нравилось, что мы обобщили все эти вещи, а также что они могли рассказать о своих опасениях, что NPHI может предложить министерству, правительству и т.д. Мы также подготовили документ об этом и представили его на
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: stakeholder workshop
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. семинаре с заинтересованными сторонами.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: They really discussed it.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Они очень активно участвовали в обсуждении.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Their concern, of course, we presented that to the leadership of the NPHI and the Ministry of Health hey These are the things.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Мы, конечно, донесли их опасения до руководства NPHI и Министерства здравоохранения. Речь про то,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: that people are saying about the NPHI, these are their concern and so they came to the counterpart workshop with some of the answers and we let the stakeholder themselves come up with their idea on how to overcome the challenges that the NPHI could meet.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. что люди говорят о NPHI, что их волнует. Поэтому они пришли на семинар с партнерами, чтобы услышать ответы на некоторые вопросы, и мы позволили заинтересованным сторонам самим предложить свои идеи о том, как преодолеть проблемы, которые могут быть решены в рамках NPHI.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Yes, and that was really interesting and.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Семинар был очень интересным.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: At the stakeholder workshop again, as I said at the beginning, really wanted there buy-in.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. И, опять же, одной из целей его проведения было привлечение заинтересованных сторон.
Claire Standley (she/her): yeah.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). Да.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: We wanted their ownership of it, we wanted their ideas on how to handle the establishment of the NPHI and we got that. And people were happy to participate and tell us what they wanted to do.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Мы хотели, чтобы они взяли на себя ответственность, мы хотели узнать их идеи о том, как лучше всего создать NPHI, и эти цели были достигнуты. И люди были рады принять участие и рассказать нам, что они хотят сделать.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Okay, so, and then the Roundtable partners Roundtable we had.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Затем мы провели круглый стол с партнерами.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Two partners roundtables so far and we are planning others. The first one again it was to explain to them, where we were, what the NPHI was doing.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Точнее, мы провели уже два круглых стола и планируем еще. millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Прежде всего, мы разъяснили им текущую ситуацию и рассказали, чем занимается NPHI.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: What are the achievement so far etc and the second one was really to brainstorm to discuss with them what they can bring to the NPHI and what the NPHI can offer to them.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Рассказали про достижения на данный момент и т.д., а второй круглый стол проводился в виде мозгового штурма, чтобы обсудить с ними, что они могут привнести в NPHI и что NPHI может предложить им.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: In the win, win approach.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Это взаимовыгодное сотрудничество.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Yes, was very important.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Да, это очень важно.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: The NPHI had to explain.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Нужно было объяснить, что такое NPHI.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Their strengths, what they can do they have laboratories, they have a researcher, they have very high level people.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Их сильные стороны, что они могут сделать: ведь у них есть лаборатории, научные сотрудники, специалисты очень высокого уровня.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: They explain to the stakeholder what they bring to the table and vice versa.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Они объясняют заинтересованным сторонам, что они привносят в работу, и наоборот.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Yes.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Да.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: So this is what I would say, related to the approach.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Вот что я бы сказал по поводу подхода.
Claire Standley (she/her): And it sounds I think a piece, I just want to follow up on is, you mentioned that there will be more partner
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). Я бы хотела еще раз уточнить сказанное. Вы говорите, что будут проводиться дальнейшие
Claire Standley (she/her): meetings and you.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). встречи с партнерами.
Claire Standley (she/her): Know stakeholder identification is is one piece, but, of course, then there's the maintenance of the relationships right.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). Определение заинтересованных сторон, конечно, важно, но за этим следует поддержание отношений.
Claire Standley (she/her): Could you speak a little bit to how the mph I and and perhaps even specifically the PHEOC continues to engage these different stakeholders and how that communication and coordination.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). Не могли бы Вы подробнее остановиться о том, как именно PHEOC (операционный штаб в сфере общественного здравоохранения) продолжает привлекать заинтересованных сторон и обеспечивать коммуникации и координацию.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Yes, I for what important is in addition to.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Да, это важное дополнение.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: To the one on one meeting with stakeholders in addition to the stakeholder workshop and roundtable we went to the organization, for example.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. На одной из встреч с заинтересованными сторонами в дополнение к семинару и круглому столу мы, например, отправились в организацию.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: We went to do so, all in the office all the staff was there and again we discussed with them, and you know the WHO person would say Oh, maybe I do not have funds for you.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Там присутствовали все сотрудники, и мы еще раз провели обсуждение с ними. И тогда представитель ВОЗ сказала, что, скорее всего, у него не будет для нас средств.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: And i'll say.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. На что я ответил,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Oh, we do not need funds from you, we need your influence you can influence people.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. что нам не нужны деньги – нам нужно влияние, поскольку они могут влиять на людей.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: yeah and yeah and she directed etc, the representative she did a great job whenever people are gathered they will say hey do not forget forget the NPHI that can do this, and this, and this that was fantastic.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. И она помогла нам, рассказывая на каждом публичном выступлении о роли и функциях NPHI. И это было просто здорово.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: And where do we begin the people like that the organization structure before leaving we asked for the name and the contact of the point person.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. И теперь в каждой организации мы перед уходом спрашиваем имя и контакты такого ключевого сотрудника.
yeah.
Да.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: And then the discussion continues with that one person, the partners, we did that, with the partner we did that, with the government social also the hospitals, etc.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. После чего обсуждение продолжается с одним человеком, нашим партнером. И это работает как в органах власти, так и в социальных службах, больницах и пр.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: yeah.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Да.
Claire Standley (she/her): Very cool and so, then that allows you to have that sustained communication with.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). Очень здорово, это позволяет вам поддерживать постоянную связь с
Claire Standley (she/her): stakeholders.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). заинтересованными сторонами.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Here there are the news newsletter there are there is the.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. У нас есть новостная рассылка и
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Facebook.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. страница в Facebook.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: yeah facebook, the website etc yeah you can go to the to the website and see what the NPHI is doing, you can see, the strategic plan, you can see the dashboard etc So these are these all these things are communicating the stakeholders in fact yeah.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Да, Facebook., веб-сайт и пр. Вы можете зайти на веб-сайт, узнать, чем занимается NPHI, увидеть стратегический план, информационную панель и пр. То есть фактически мы всю эту информацию доносим до заинтересованных сторон.
Claire Standley (she/her): yeah so last question for you just quickly you know, based on your experiences what advice would you give to an EOC, a public health EOC that's trying to engage more with stakeholders in its in its region or country.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). И последний вопрос к Вам. Очень кратко, пожалуйста, основываясь на вашем опыте, скажите, какой совет Вы бы дали операционному штабу в сфере общественного здравоохранения, который пытается больше взаимодействовать с заинтересованными сторонами в своем регионе или стране.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: To tell you the truth, I asked the question to our EOC Director.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Если честно, этот же самый вопрос я задавал директору нашего операционного штаба.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: I went to him and asked him what would you recommend and he said Okay, yes, the national level is the coordination level.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Я подошел к нему и задал тот же вопрос, что бы он порекомендовал. Он ответил, что координация осуществляется на национальном уровне.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: yeah is where is the strategic level the coordination level, you really need to engage the sub national level until the Community that is what he said and.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Стратегический уровень – это координационный уровень. Но нам нужно активно задействовать субнациональный уровень, до уровня местных сообществ.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: He also said that documentation written documents specific specifying role and responsibilities at all level is key.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Он также добавил, что еще одной ключевой функцией является подготовка документов, в которых прописаны роли и обязанности.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: And this is was.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Это и было
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: One of his suggestions and recommendations. and he also said that yes, training of course, is important and I forgot that part.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. одним из его предложений и рекомендаций. Да, еще он говорил о важности обучения, я про это совсем забыл.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: It is not enough to involve people, you need to train them.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Недостаточно просто привлекать людей – нужно обучать их.
To.
Точно.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: The sub national level, for example, they were waiting on emergency management etc so training also is important, what.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. На субнациональном уровне, например, им необходим был тренинг по управлению чрезвычайными ситуациями.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: I could say.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Я бы сказал, это важно.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Best practice.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Передовой опыт.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: According to him, it was the involvement of the military.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. По его мнению, это было привлечение военных.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: yeah the military is so that they can access  the zone, the areas with security issues.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Военные имеют доступ в зоны, где есть проблемы с безопасностью.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: For invetsigation, they were they were.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Они могут проводить спасательные операции
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: very helpful on that and they even created RRT team, a rapid response team within the army, yes, so to deal with the military camps and the lab, because they have medical structure, they have labs, the military structures so the lab also participated in the in the, for example.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. и даже создали службу экстренного реагирования на базе войск. И, поскольку у них есть военные базы и лаборатории, медицинские подразделения, все это можно также использовать, например,
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: In the management of the COVID-19.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. в реагировании на  COVID-19.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: yeah yeah and what else.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Да, что еще.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: They involved, maybe not only the.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Они не только
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Traditional people structure, but they really did think out of the box.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. использовали традиционные структуры, но и предлагали нестандартные решения.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: In a.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. В
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: situation, what are the group that really need to be involved, for example, the, the body in charge of the government body in charge of humanitarian response.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. ситуации, когда действительно было необходимо участие группы, например, правительственной группы, ответственной за гуманитарный отклик.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: yeah I was, IT people, yes, of course, it is currently we cannot do anything without.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Еще нужно упомянуть сотрудников ИТ, потому что сейчас невозможно ничего сделать
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: IT. And again, at least for the Burkina Faso context, the faith and opportune leaders
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. без ИТ. Опять-таки, минимум в контексте Буркина-Фасо, религиозные лидеры и лидеры мнений играют
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: yeah, if you want your Community members to accept the measure some time, it is hard on them.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. важную роль, когда необходимо убедить местные сообщества принять те или иные меры.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: You need to go through the faith and opportune leaders.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Нужно обращаться к таким лидерам.
Claire Standley (she/her): yeah yeah.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). Точно.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: And it shows in the most success if the iman and the leader say Oh, you know that it is difficult, this, but it is important for us to start distancing etc, etc, people will understand it and follow.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. А самого большого успеха можно добиться, если религиозные и правительственные лидеры говорят, что, мол, да, это трудно, но вы же понимаете важность социальной дистанции и т.д. и т.п. И тогда люди поймут и будут выполнять.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: Yes, this is what he told me as suggestion ideas.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Вот такие мысли он мне озвучил.
Claire Standley (she/her): Well, thank you so much, and please thank him as well on on our behalf for his input to this.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). Большое спасибо Вам и поблагодарите его также от нашего имени за проделанную работу.
Claire Standley (she/her): And we're incredibly grateful once again for your time today and your expertise and I'm sure we'll we'll follow up if there's any additional questions, but thank you once again for your time today.
Клэр Стэндли (она/ее). Я еще раз хочу выразить огромную благодарность за уделенное время и за то, что поделились своим опытом. Я уверена, что мы еще раз встретимся, если появятся новые вопросы, а пока спасибо, что пришли к нам.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr: It was a pleasure for me.
millogoclaude@yahoo.fr. Мне тоже было очень приятно.